Sackville-West, V. mss., 1888-1962 LMC 1896
Lilly Library
Sackville-West, V. mss.
1888-1962
1985
Lilly Library
Sackville-West, V. (Victoria), 1892-1962
LMC 1896
13 Boxes
The Sackville-West, V. mss., 1888-1962, consist of the letters of author Victoria Mary (Vita) Sackville-West, 1892-1962, and her husband, Sir Harold George Nicolson, 1886-1968, author.
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Biographical Note
Victoria Mary (Vita) Sackville-West, 1892-1962, was an author-horticulturalist known for her poem "The Land" as well as over 50 other works. Sackville-West and her husband, author Sir Harold George Nicolson (1886-1968), were active members of the Bloomsbury group as well as avid gardeners.
Lady Sackville (Victoria Josephine Sackville-West), 1862-1936, was Victoria (Vita) Sackville-West's mother and a close friend of artist Auguste Rodin.
Arrangement
Arranged chronologically within each series.
Scope and Content Note
The Sackville-West, V. mss., 1888-1962, consist of the letters of author Victoria Mary (Vita) Sackville-West, 1892-1962, and her husband, Sir Harold George Nicolson, 1886-1968, author. Also present are diaries and engagement books of Victoria Sackville-West for the years 1907-1929 and diaries of her mother, Lady Sackville (Victoria Josephine Sackville-West, 1862-1936), for the years 1888-1935.
Note on Indexing Term "Bloomsbury Group": A few letters from Virginia Woolf are also present.
Related Material
See Sackville-West mss. and Trefusis mss., also located at the Lilly Library, Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana.
Acquisition Information
Purchase: 1985
Bloomsbury Group; English Poetry; Women; Sackville-West, V. (Victoria), 1892-1962; Nicolson, Harold, 1886-1968; Sackville, Victoria Josephine Sackville-West, Lady, 1862-1936
- Correspondence
  - 1910-1919, June (Box 1)
  - July 1919-June 1926 (Box 2)
  - July 1926-January 1928 (Box 3)
  - February 1928- June 1935 (Box 4)
  - July 1935-November 1940 (Box 5)
  - December 1940-1945 (Box 6)
  - 1946-1951 (Box 7)
  - 1952-October 1961 (Box 8)
  - November 1961-1968 (Box 9)
- Diaries, Engagement Books, Reminiscences
  - Diaries and engagement books: Vita Sackville-West, 1907-1933; (22 volumes) (Box 10)
  - Diaries and reminiscences: Lady Sackville, 1922; 1889-1909; (13 volumes) (Box 10)
  - Diaries: Lady Sackville, 1911-1 March 1932; (15 volumes) (Box 11)
  - Diaries: Lady Sackville, 3 March 1932-April 1935; (7 volumes) (Box 12)
  - Diaries: Lady Sackville, May 1935-June 1936; (3 volumes) (Box 13)
  - Stories, 1934-1935 (Box 13)
  - Autograph book, 1918-1928 (Box 13)